

CONTACTS

chornyalexander@gmail.com

www.chorny-alexander/

Alexander Chorny

Vinnitsa, Ukraine

SKILLS

- HTML / CSS
 - responsive
 - valid
 - cross-browser
- Bootstrap
- JavaScript
- TypeScript
- React.js
 - Next.js
- Redux
- Figma, Photoshop
- Git

LANGUAGES

- English Upper-Intermediate
- German Intermediate
- Ukrainian **Native**
- Russian Native

ALEXANDER CHORNY

WEB DEVELOPER

PROFILE

I'm a passionate developer with relevant experience in web development. I focus on creating reliable, adaptive, cross-browser web products, emphasizing best practices and accessibility.

In life, I enjoy self-learning, constantly working on improving my technical and communication skills. I strive to learn something new or accomplish something useful every day.

Additionally, I enjoy sports and pursuing diverse personal development opportunities.

EXPERIENCE

Apr 2024 - Jul 2024

Freelance Web Developer

Participated in a project involving the creation and management of databases. Refined the functionality of a code editor based on CodeMirror, implementing combined language support (SQL and JavaScript) with syntax highlighting and autocompletion. Contributed to various other project features.

Skills Used and Improved: React \cdot CodeMirror \cdot TypeScript \cdot JavaScript \cdot Lezer \cdot Recoil \cdot Git \cdot Codespaces \cdot Ant Design.

Jan 2023 - Dec 2023

Freelance Web Developer

1. ONE-OF-PRO (Tech Job Platform) – teamwork;

2. MYHOBBY-ECOMMERSE (store) - I work independently.

Skills Used and Improved: React \cdot Next.js \cdot Docker \cdot TypeScript \cdot GraphQL \cdot MongoDB \cdot Jest \cdot GitHub/Codespaces \cdot GitHub/task-board.

Jul 2009 - Feb 2022

MYHOBBY

Consultant/Content Manager

Website maintenance, consultations, sales, purchase of goods.

Apr 2015 - Jun 2015

APPAREL EXPRESS

Improvement Of A Website

 $Improvement\ of\ website\ design\ and\ functionality.$

Refinement of the order sorting module.

Dec 2014 - Feb 2015

KRAINEVA ANASTASIA

Website Development

Website development for an artist.

EDUCATION

August 2024 - November 2024 | USA

Front End Development Libraries

September 2022 - August 2024 | USA

JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures

Responsive Web Design

Free Code Camp

September 1991 - May 1994 | Ukraine (Vinnitsa)

Maintenance of electrical installations

Vocational and Technical Education Center No. 1